Furkan Tunalı Résumé

Summary

I've been developing the web whether it's frontend, back-end, or designing things in multidisciplinary ways, mentoring, consulting or handling clients more than ten years.

As years went by and I've become more enthusiastic and experienced, I honed my skills within the projects, companies or clients that I've worked on the web field without strict limiting my area of work.

More recently, my primary focus has leaned towards developing software with JavaScript besides building and managing front-end architectures.

Info

Fullname: Mustafa Furkan Tunalı

Available working permits: 4 years of Blue Card EU Residential and Working Permit holder and Turkish Citizenship

Current residency: Berlin

Contact

• Web: FurkanTunali.com

• E-mail: mail@furkantunali.com

• Phone: +49 174 6492854

• LinkedIn

• GitHub

Experiences

Front-end Team Lead at Groupe
 Chantelle, Digital Lab, Berlin

08/2017 - Present

Some of my tasks were:

- Managing and being responsible for the actions of Front-end team.
- HR, interview, boarding and hiring process
- Modernizing front-end architecture without losing existing functionalities and values.
- Making sure codebase is improved and streamlined.
- Implementing code quality assuring tools and automated of tests.
- Implement dev-ops tools and a new ecosystem to act develop faster.
- Helping with the conversion from monolith systems into separated microservices when possible.
- Following Agile methods.
- Reviewing codes.

- Migrating from Front-end to being a Fullstack team.
- Mentoring, inspiring, guiding or helping front-end team when possible.
- Helping to achieve being data-driven and implementing A/B testing solutions.
- Making sure the projects will be fitted into sprints and acting if they are not going as planned.
- Tracking the development of UI library for connecting UX team and Front-end team components as a bridge.

Some of the technology and services that I used so far:

- Node, Magento, WebPack, React, GraphQL, Redux, FlowType, AWS, Koa, MongoDB, Babel, Functional Programming, Atlassian tools, Github
- Universal JavaScript Engineer at Pixsy GmbH, Berlin

01/2017 - 08/2017

My responsibilities were:

- Delivering new features on both ends with using JavaScript.
- Delivering code with the unit, integration and E2E covered tests.
- Maintaining or migrating existing features.
- Developing and maintaining microservices.
- Improving our architecture and stack when its possible.
- Integrating and maintaining data on Mongo, Stripe and SalesForce.
- Keeping an eye on app health with Heroku and Sentry reports.
- Following KANBAN with some Agile methods.

- Reviewing codes from our team's pull requests.
- Following our code conventions and guidelines.

Some of the technology and services that I used:

- Node, Lambda/Serverless, React, Redux, FlowType, AWS, WebPack, Webpack Isomorphic Tools, Koa, MongoDB, Babel, HighlandJS, SalesForce API, Mixpanel, Mocha, Chai, Yadda, Webdriver.io on top of Selenium, Stripe API, Sentry, Github
- Software Architect and JavaScript Developer at <u>Talented Square</u>, <u>CA</u>

08/2015 - 08/2016

Some of the projects:

 Front-end development for a giant multinational retail corporation's online wholesale seller portal which cannot disclose its name but feel free to contact for the details.

Some of the project skills: JavaScript, Angular, AMD, Gulp, CSS, SCSS, HTML and small of amount of Maven and Jetty.

 Performance and architectural improvements and JavaScript development to an e-commerce website to the same company described above.

Some of the project skills: Browser and mobile optimisation, JavaScript, Backbone, AMD, CSS, jQuery, HTML and Ant.

 Architectural design and javascript development for a new recruiting startup project.

Some of the project skills: architectural decisions, JavaScript, LoopBack, Webpack, Gulp, MySql, React, Redux, HTML, SCSS.

 Founder, full stack web developer and designer at <u>NOD studios</u>, <u>Istanbul</u>

11/2012 - 07/2015

Some of the projects:

Web development and design for <u>Gym & Tonic</u>

Some of the project skills: Design, JavaScript, PHP, HTML, LESS, CSS, CanJS, Mustache.

Web development for <u>Silent + Blessed</u>

Some of the project skills: Design, JavaScript, HTML, LESS, CSS, CanJS, Mustache.

Web development and design for <u>Mirjam</u>
 <u>Schmitt</u>

Some of the project skills: Design, JavaScript, HTML, LESS, CSS, CanJS, Mustache, Wordpress, Wordpress JSON API.

Web development and design and UX consultancy for <u>Les Benjamins</u>

Some of the project skills: Wireframing, Mockup, Design, JavaScript, HTML, LESS, CSS, CanJS,

Mustache, CakePHP.

 Web development, design, mobile app design, UX design and refactoring legacy code for <u>etiqadd</u>

Some of the project skills: Wireframing, Design, JavaScript, AMD, PHP, Codelgniter

 Social web app design and gamification for <u>Gripati</u>

Some of the project skills: Wireframing, Design, JavaScript, AMD, PHP, Codelgniter

 Front-end mobile web development for <u>LigTV</u>

Some of the project skills: Mobile optimisation, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

 Internal website design and full stack web development for <u>Ülker</u>

Some of the project skills: PHP, CakePHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

 Server side web RSS aggregator API development for a mobile app of <u>MB Apps</u>

Some of the project skills: CakePHP, PHP

Full stack web development for <u>Umut</u>
 <u>Üzümleri</u> movie

Some of the project skills: Design, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

- Open source projects and libraries at Github
- Full stack web developer at FOX
 International Channels, Istanbul

01/2012 - 12/2012

Development of some social app and microsite web development for some clients including:

<u>Samsung Turkey</u>, <u>National Geographic</u> <u>Turkey</u>, <u>Nokia Turkey</u>, <u>True Blood TV show</u>, <u>Glee TV Show</u>, <u>TerraNova TV show</u> Front-end developer and designer at projectz, Istanbul

06/2011 - 12/2011

Front-end coding, refactoring and web design for startup project <u>vardimlazim.com</u>

 Full stack developer at Manajans / JWT, Istanbul

05/2009 - 06/2011

Development of websites, CMS development, online communities, social apps and microsites for some clients including:

Miller, GncTurkcell / Turkcell, Eston, First, Bomonti, Efes, TeraBrokers (Formerly TeraMenkul)

Front-end developer at <u>Tribal DDB</u>
 Worldwide Istanbul(formerly
 Manadigital)

03/2009 - 05/2009

Front-end development for some clients including:

patlican / avea, TTNET

Full stack developer at Ping Digital
 Agency Istanbul (formerly OnKaplan)

05/2008 - 03/2009

Garanti, TTNET

 Designer, front-end and Flash developer at Koçak Dizayn, Istanbul

05/2008 - 03/2009

Design, concept art creation, front-end development and illustration for an online art community startup.

 Designer and front-end developer at MedyaNova, Istanbul

05/2005 - 02/2007

Design and front-end web development for various web projects mostly regarding travelling, hotel and hotel franchise clients like <u>Best Western Hotels</u>.

• Internship at MedyaNova, Istanbul

04/2005 - 05/2005

Skills

- Programming & Development
 - Software & Markup Languages
 - JavaScript / ECMAScript,
 EcmaScript 2016 / ES6,
 EcmaScript 2017 / ES7 advanced
 - <u>Node.js</u> advanced
 - PHP advanced
 - <u>HTML</u> / <u>HTML5</u> / <u>xHTML</u> advanced
 - CSS / CSS3, less, SASS / SCSS advanced

- Python beginner
- <u>Ruby</u> beginner
- <u>SQL</u> advanced
- Familiar patterns / conventions: FP, Isomorphic / Universal Javascript, TDD, BDD, MVC, MVVM, OOP, Prototypal OOP, OLOO, AOP, ES6 Modules, AMD, CommonJS, Semantic Versioning
- Other: Bash, ASP, .NET, C, C++, PIC

Tools

Some of the frameworks

- RxJS (beginner)
- Serverless for Lambda (advanced)
- <u>Koa</u> (intermediate)
- React (advanced)
- Redux (advanced)
- Flux (intermediate)
- Angular (advanced)
- Backbone (advanced)
- CanJS (advanced)

- polymer (intermediate)
- Aurelia (beginner)
- express (intermediate)
- LoopBack (advanced)
- CakePHP (advanced)
- <u>lithium</u> (intermediate)
- Codelgniter (intermediate)

Databases

- RethinkDB beginner
- MongoDB advanced
- MySQL advanced
- <u>SQLite</u> advanced

Libraries and Miscellaneous Tools

Flow Type, Atom, npm, Homebrew,
Babel, gulp, Jest, Chai Assertion
Library, webpack, HighlandJS,
WebStorm, Protractor, jQuery,
RequireJS, Underscore.js / lodash, git,
PM2, Wordpress, IBM API Connect,
Bower, SystemJS, jspm, composer, pip,

gem, Apache Http Server, PhoneGap, Appcelerator, fish, Bash

APIs and Services

Heroku, AWS (Amazon Web Services), SalesForce, Stripe, Mixpanel, Facebook, Twitter, Shopify, Flickr, Tumblr, WP REST API, SoundCloud, Pinterest

Operating Systems

OS X, Ubuntu, Windows (Using it for playing some video games)

Design

- Web Design on the browser
- Ul Design
- Wireframing / Mockup Design
- Responsive Design
- UI Design
- Web UX
- Branding / Identity

- Print Design
- Tools
 - Adobe Photoshop advanced
 - <u>Sketch</u> *beginner*
 - Adobe Illustrator advanced
 - Adobe Fireworks intermediate
- Languages
 - Turkish native
 - English advanced

Education

 Computer Programming and Technology at <u>Kadir Has University</u>

2004 - 2008

Sehremini Anadolu High School

Interests

- DJ and Founder at AmbientData
- Contributing back to an <u>Open source</u>
- Experimenting with side-projects
- Sci-Fi books, movies etc.
- Exploring <u>Typography</u>
- Photo manipulation
- Travelling
- Exploring Craft Beer and Coffee
- Video games
- Any kind of nerd activity